Miranda Melton

mahanesme@gmail.com / 980-355-2541 / Fort Mill, SC 29715

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/melton-miranda

GitHub: https://github.com/meltonme/

Summary

Data Analyst who is able to utilize analytical mindset and newly acquired skills in data manipulation and interpretation. Able to contribute to a data-driven environment to uncover insights and drive business decisions through data analysis.

Technical Skills

Languages: Python, R, SQL, JavaScript, HTML5

Tools: MongoDB, PostgreSQL, AWS, Flask, Shiny, Tableau, Excel, Seaborn, TensorFlow, Jupyter Notebook,

Leaflet.js, SQLAlchemy, Pandas, NumPy, Scikit-Learn, Matplotlib, Plotly and Plotly.Express

Skills: Data visualization, data analysis, machine learning, database management

Projects

Crime Prediction Model for Charlotte, North Carolina (2017-2024)

https://github.com/meltonme/Crime-Predictions

- Summary: Explored and analyzed crime patterns in Charlotte, NC from 2017-2024, creating a
 predictive model that forecasted crime types and locations
- Role: Worked in a team of three to perform data cleansing procedures and create relevant visualizations
- Tools: Python, Pandas, PostgreSQL, scikit-learn, Jupyter Notebook, Tableau Public, City of Charlotte Data Portal, Random Forest, zipfile

Understanding COVID-19 Variants in European Countries

https://github.com/MahnFrammen/Project-3

- Summary: Investigation into the emergence and concentration of COVID-19 variants in six European countries between 2020-2024
- Role: Worked in a team of three to assist with data cleansing, develop the SQL database, and create relevant visualizations
- Tools: Python, Requests, Pandas, NumPy, JSON, Plotly and Plotly. Express, Ipywidgets, Math, Seaborn, Covid19 Novel API, PostgreSQL, Jupyter Notebook

NFL Sports Betting

https://github.com/meltonme/nfl_sports_betting_analysis

- Summary: Explored and quantified the influence of different factors on sportsbook game spreads and over/under totals
- Role: Worked in a team of three to assist with data cleansing and complete an analysis on stadium and team statistics
- Tools: Jupyter Notebook, Python, Pandas, Matplotlib, NumPy, Pathlib, Scipy.stats, Seaborn

Professional Experience

Operations Lead2023-PresentCDAO CircleCharlotte, NC

- Assisted in the development and planning of 4 regional and 1 national summits and conclaves for data and analytics C-Suite executives
- Maintained relationships with 25 Advisory and Executive Board members, event attendees, and outside business partners
- Contributed to strategic planning sessions and provided critical input on operational efficiency and event coordination
- Developed and maintained a database to store information on 100+ CDAOs (Chief Data Analytics Officers) and other data/AI executives

Administrative Specialist

2022-2023

Lowe's Companies, Inc.

Mooresville, NC

- Provided administrative support to retail executives and teams, handling calendar management, meeting scheduling, and confidential correspondence
- Supported 15 teams in the successful executive of the 'Buy-More-Save-More' promotion for the 2022 holiday season
- Collaborated with Chief-of-Staff to conduct thorough audits of organization processes, identifying areas for improvement, and implementing corrective actions
- Gathered, entered, and updated data to maintain organization records and databases

Orchestra Teacher2017-2022Charlotte-Mecklenburg SchoolsCharlotte, NC

- Developed and implemented a comprehensive music curriculum tailored for 200+ middle school students, catering to diverse learning needs, including students with special needs
- Partnered with the Fine Arts Department and acted as Arts Booster Liaison for PTA to advocate for music education, promote program offerings through digital media, and explore opportunities for enhancement
- Engaged with parents, administrators, and special education teachers to collect and organize data for students with IEPs and 504 Plans, resulting in zero missed submission deadlines and 95% stakeholder satisfaction
- Coordinated Professional Learning Community (PLC) meetings as a department co-chair, facilitating meaningful professional development opportunities and elevating the overall quality of instruction

Education

Certificate, Data Analytics: University of North Carolina at Charlotte, Charlotte, NC 2024 **Bachelor of Music, Music Education:** Appalachian State University, Boone, NC 2014-2017